$(document).ready(function() {
    // console.log( "ready!" );

    // track which question we are on
    var questionCounter = 0;
    // initial time of 15 seconds for each question
    var time = 15;
    // will keep tally of right guesses for end game
    var correctGuesses = 0;
    //will keep tally of wrong guesses for end game
    var incorrectGuesses = 0;

    // question & answer array
    var questions = [
        {
            question: "what is the final evolution of dratini?",
            choices: ["Dragonite", "Gyarados", "Dragonair", "Charizard"],
            correctAnswer: "Dragonite",
            image: "<img src='assets/images/dragonite.gif'>"
          }, 
        
      {
	    question: "What were the names of the twins from Rugrats?",
	    choices: ["Lil and Phil", "Harry and Larry", "Manny and Sally", "Henry and Billy"],
	    correctAnswer: "Lil and Phil",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/rugrats.gif'>"
	  }, 
	  {
	    question: "What is the name of the dad in The Wild Thornberrys?",
	    choices: ["Roger", "Nigel", "Daniel", "Phillip"],
	    correctAnswer: "Nigel",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/dad.gif'>"
	  }, 
	  {
	    question: "What is the name of The Last Airbender?",
	    choices: ["Sokka", "Azula", "Zhao", "Aang"],
	    correctAnswer: "Aang",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/aang.gif'>"
	  }, 
	  {
	    question: "What was the name of the teacher on the magic school bus?",
	    choices: ["Miss Frizzle", "Miss Dorthy", "Miss Pepper", "Miss Frizzle"],
	    correctAnswer: "Miss Frizzle",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/teacher.gif'>"
	  }, 
	  {
	    question: "Who are the main characters on The Simpsons?",
	    choices: ["Homer, Marge, Lisa & Maggie", "Homer, Marge, Lisa, Bart & Mage", "Homer, Marge, Lisa, Bart & Maggie", "Homer, Marj, Lisa, Bart & Maggie"],
	    correctAnswer: "Homer, Marge, Lisa, Bart & Maggie",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/simpsons.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "What was the name of the purple ninja turtle?",
	    choices: ["Raphael", "Leonardo", "Donatello", "Michelangelo"],
	    correctAnswer: "Donatello",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/donatello.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "What is the name of the fifth grade genius always inventing some new gadget with his robot dog?",
	    choices: ["Timmy Turner", "Jimmy Turner", "Carl Wheezer", "Jimmy Neutron"],
	    correctAnswer: "Jimmy Neutron",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/jimmy.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "What is the name of the main character in American Dragon?",
	    choices: ["Jake Lee", "Kim Long", "Jake Long", "Lin Wang"],
	    correctAnswer: "Jake Long",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/jake.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "Who are the villians in Emperor's New Groove?",
	    choices: ["Klonk & Elma", "Kronk & Yzma", "Klong &  Yzma", "Krank & Zema"],
	    correctAnswer: "Kronk & Yzma",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/kronk.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "Penny Proud is the main character of what Cartoon?",
	    choices: ["Family Guy", "Regular Show", "Proud Family", "Rick & Morty"],
	    correctAnswer: "Proud Family",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/penny.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "What is the name of Spongebob's pet snail?",
	    choices: ["Slimy", "Gary", "Patrick", "Tony"],
	    correctAnswer: "Gary",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/gary.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "Who is Kim Possible's Arch-Nemesis?",
	    choices: ["Se√±or Senior Jr.,", "Monkey Fist", " Shego", "Ron Stoppable"],
	    correctAnswer: "Shego",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/shego.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "What is Stitch's experiment number, from 'Lilo and Stitch'?",
	    choices: ["626", "262", "186", "681"],
	    correctAnswer: "626",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/stitch.gif'>"
	  },
	  {
	    question: "Which brother from Phineas and Ferb had green hair?",
	    choices: ["Phineas", "Ferb"],
	    correctAnswer: "Ferb",
	    image: "<img src='assets/images/ferb.gif'>"
	  }];
	  

	// create question contents according to question count
	function questionContent() {
		// a for loop would be cool here...
    	$("#gameScreen").append("<p><strong>" + 
    		questions[questionCounter].question + 
    		"</p><p class='choices'>" + 
    		questions[questionCounter].choices[0] + 
    		"</p><p class='choices'>" + 
    		questions[questionCounter].choices[1] + 
    		"</p><p class='choices'>" + 
    		questions[questionCounter].choices[2] + 
    		"</p><p class='choices'>" + 
    		questions[questionCounter].choices[3] + 
    		"</strong></p>");
	}

	// user guessed correctly
	function userWin() {
		$("#gameScreen").html("<p>You got it right!</p>");
		correctGuesses++;
		var correctAnswer = questions[questionCounter].correctAnswer;
		$("#gameScreen").append("<p>The answer was <span class='answer'>" + 
			correctAnswer + 
			"</span></p>" + 
			questions[questionCounter].image);
		setTimeout(nextQuestion, 4000);
		questionCounter++;
	}

	// user guessed incorrectly
	function userLoss() {
		$("#gameScreen").html("<p>Nope, that's not it!</p>");
		incorrectGuesses++;
		var correctAnswer = questions[questionCounter].correctAnswer;
		$("#gameScreen").append("<p>The answer was <span class='answer'>" + 
			correctAnswer + 
			"</span></p>" + 
			questions[questionCounter].image);
		setTimeout(nextQuestion, 4000);
		questionCounter++;
	}

	// user ran out of time
	function userTimeout() {
		if (time === 0) {
			$("#gameScreen").html("<p>You ran out of time!</p>");
			incorrectGuesses++;
			var correctAnswer = questions[questionCounter].correctAnswer;
			$("#gameScreen").append("<p>The answer was <span class='answer'>" + 
				correctAnswer + 
				"</span></p>" + 
				questions[questionCounter].image);
			setTimeout(nextQuestion, 4000);
			questionCounter++;
		}
	}

	// screen that shows final score and nice message :)
	function resultsScreen() {
		if (correctGuesses === questions.length) {
			var endMessage = "Perfection! Might want to go outside more tho";
			var bottomText = "#nerdalert!";
		}
		else if (correctGuesses > incorrectGuesses) {
			var endMessage = "Good work! But do better you can...";
			var bottomText = "all your base are belong to us";
		}
		else {
			var endMessage = "You seem to have taken an arrow to the knee";
			var bottomText = "#scrub";
		}
		$("#gameScreen").html("<p>" + endMessage + "</p>" + "<p>You got <strong>" + 
			correctGuesses + "</strong> right.</p>" + 
			"<p>You got <strong>" + incorrectGuesses + "</strong> wrong.</p>");
		$("#gameScreen").append("<h1 id='start'>Start Over?</h1>");
		$("#bottomText").html(bottomText);
		gameReset();
		$("#start").click(nextQuestion);
	}

	// game clock currently set to 15 seconds
	function timer() {
		clock = setInterval(countDown, 1000);
		function countDown() {
			if (time < 1) {
				clearInterval(clock);
				userTimeout();
			}
			if (time > 0) {
				time--;
			}
			$("#timer").html("<strong>" + time + "</strong>");
		}
	}

	// moves question counter forward to show next question
	function nextQuestion() {
		if (questionCounter < questions.length) {
			time = 15;
			$("#gameScreen").html("<p>You have <span id='timer'>" + time + "</span> seconds left!</p>");
			questionContent();
			timer();
			userTimeout();
		}
		else {
			resultsScreen();
		}
	// console.log(questionCounter);
	// console.log(questions[questionCounter].correctAnswer);
	}

	// reset score and counter parameters on restart
	function gameReset() {
		questionCounter = 0;
		correctGuesses = 0;
		incorrectGuesses = 0;
	}

    function startGame() {
    	$("#gameScreen").html("<p>You have <span id='timer'>" + time + "</span> seconds left!</p>");
    	$("#start").hide();
    	// $("#gameScreen").append("<div id='question'>");
    	// var nextQuestion = questionContent(questionCounter);
    	// $("#gameScreen").append(nextQuestion);

		// $("#gameScreen").append("<p>" + questions[questionCounter].question + "</p><p>" + questions[questionCounter].choices[0] + "</p><p>" + questions[questionCounter].choices[1] + "</p><p>" + questions[questionCounter].choices[2] + "</p><p>" + questions[questionCounter].choices[3] + "</p>");
		// questionCounter++;
		questionContent();
    	timer();
    	userTimeout();
    }

    // this starts the game
    $("#start").click(nextQuestion);

    // click function to trigger right or wrong screen
	$("#gameScreen").on("click", ".choices", (function() {
		// alert("clicked!");
		var userGuess = $(this).text();
		if (userGuess === questions[questionCounter].correctAnswer) {
			clearInterval(clock);
			userWin();
		}
		else {
			clearInterval(clock);
			userLoss();
		}
	}));
});